## **Shailesh Das**

Hyderabad | shailo199925@gmail.com | 7001794582 | LinkedIn | GitHub

### **SUMMARY**

A software engineer with 3+ years of experience, with 2 years in designing, developing, and maintaining scalable software systems and applications. Experienced Full Stack Developer trained in Java, Javascript, and software development methodologies such as Agile and Scrum along with software deployment and maintenance. Built Client Side Product Configuration Screens which led to faster implementation of client-specific configs by 80% and reduced dependency on the Product Team.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Senior Member Technical - ADP Pvt. Ltd. - Hyderabad - Hybrid

Oct 2023 - Present

- Responsible for R&D of the next gen Low Code Platform in the Lifion Product team.
- Develop Scalable HCM solutions for international clients such as Amazon, Atos, etc.
- Develop enhancements, Resolve bugs in the current product platform.
- Migrate clients to the next gen Lifion Product.

#### Associate Software Engineer 1 - Highradius Technologies Pvt. Ltd. - Hyderabad - On-site

June 2021 - Oct 2023

- Worked in the Product teams of Deductions Management System(DMS) and Claims And POD Automation (CPA) of Highradius, with 100+ clients.
- Designed and developed a REST API Framework using NodeJS that reduces web posting time by 40%.
- Deployed Log4j vulnerability fixes to production working together with relevant stakeholders within 2 days.
- Debugged software, identified root causes, and proposed solutions to software issues.
- Established a set of best practices and documented procedures for software testing, resulting in improved accuracy and reliability of software products.
- Developed a software prototype that successfully demonstrated the potential of a new research concept.
- Developed and maintained scalable software in multiple programming languages, such as Java, and JavaScript.
- Developed automated scripts to simplify common tasks and reduce manual effort by 30%.
- Led a group of interns for faster KTs and onboard them in product teams.

#### Software Engineer Intern - Highradius Technologies Pvt. Ltd. - Remote

July 2020 - June 2021

- Developed scalable applications using Java, Struts, Spring, and Hibernate as Back-end tech stacks & SQL for the database.
- Solved many Framework Bugs and Enhanced Internal frameworks for removing redundant code usage.
- Ensured coding standards, proper design patterns, writing test cases, and project management processes were followed.
- Ensured bug-free production deliverable code for the product

# SKILLS

- Functional Agile, Jira, SDLC, Confluence
- **Technical** Java 8, J2EE, Spring Boot, Python, AWS, Hibernate, MySQL, Javascript, ExtJs, System Design, Git, Microservices, Apache Maven, Apache Tomcat, NodeJs.

# **EDUCATION**

## Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology - Bhubhaneshwar

April 2021 - June 2021

• B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering - CGPA 8.14/10

#### **PROJECTS**

- **B2B Finance Software** A full-stack <u>B2B application</u> where UI was based on React Js coupled with Material-UI and the back-end was built using Java Servlets and SQL as a database. **Tech Stack: Java, ReactJs, Flask, SQL**
- Tractive A Social Safety Application The <u>application</u> sends alert messages to peers using the application by sending
  alert notifications containing the GPS location of the victims. This is an automated process invoked in the application. Tech
  Stack: Python, Arduino, Flutter.
- **Bind Vendor Seller Application (Freelancing) -** An <u>application</u> that involves vendors mainly home businesses selling to their customers, having checkout, filter, location search, etc. **Tech Stack Used: Flutter, Firebase**

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

- **Highflyer of the Quarter Intern for Q2, 2021** in HighRadius Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
- Star Team Award for Q2, 2021 in HighRadius Technologies Pvt. Ltd.